Guide to the Robert Penn Warren Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1930-85; Series II; 60; (145 boxes)
  - SHORTER WORKS
    - Interviews
      - R. P. Warren interviewed by Will Fridy, Yale University (1 of 2 cassettes), 1982 November 19; 1; 00:57:24; The program is distorted at times. High background noise can be heard on the tape. (Box 333, Item barcode 39002091249749)
        Audiovisual material. Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult access services for further information.
      - R .P. Warren interviewed by Will Fridy, Yale University (2 of 2 cassettes), 1982 November 19; 1; 00:38:49; High background noise can be heard on the tape. (Box 333, Item barcode 39002091249756)
      - Galbis, Ignacio R. M. "Una Entrevista con Robert Penn Warren": photocopy (incomplete), n.d. (Box 239, Folder 4636)
      - Gray, Chris. "A Conversation with Robert Penn Warren." The Friday News-Letter (Johns Hopkins), 1977 Mar 4 (Box 239, Folder 4637)
      - Lewis, R. W. B. "Presenting Robert Penn Warren." Poetvision (transcript of interview comments on Warren's poetry, with texts of poems), 1988 (Box 239, Folder 4638)
      - Link, Frank. "Robert Penn Warren on His Poetry": typescript, corrected, photocopy, [1967?] (Box 239, Folder 4639)
      - New England Review. "An Interview with Robert Penn Warren and Eleanor Clark", 1978 Autumn (Box 239, Folder 4640)
      - Newman, Edwin. ("Speaking Freely": WNBC Television): typescript, 1970 Dec 17 (Box 239, Folder 4641)
      - Paris Review (Ralph Ellison and Eugene Walter). "The Art of Fiction."
        - Original typescript, 1957 (Box 239, Folder 4642)
        - Revised typescript, 1957 (Box 239, Folder 4643)
        - Revised typescript, carbon, 1957 (Box 239, Folder 4644)
      - Sale, Richard. "An Interview in New Haven with Robert Penn Warren." Studies in the Novel (with Warren's annotations and letter from Sale), 1970 Fall (Box 239, Folder 4645)
      - Saporta, Marc. "Un Entretien avec Robert Penn Warren." Informations and Documents, 1961 Oct 15 (Box 240, Folder 4646)
      - Saporta, Marc. "Robert Penn Warren"
        - Typescript, n.d. (Box 240, Folder 4647)
        - Informations and Documents, 1963 Oct 1 (Box 240, Folder 4648)
      - Shapiro, Edward: typescript, photocopy, 1965 (Box 240, Folder 4649)
      - Stitt, Peter. "An Interview with Robert Penn Warren." The Sewanee Review: photocopy, 1977 Summer (Box 240, Folder 4650)
      - Tucker, Carll. Southern Review: photocopy, 1981 Jul (Box 240, Folder 4651)
      - U.S. News and World Report. "What Kind of Future for America?", 1975 Jul 7 (Box 240, Folder 4652)
      - Walker, Marshall. "Robert Penn Warren." Scottish International, 1970 Feb (Box 240, Folder 4653)
      - Walker, Marshall. "Robert Penn Warren: An Interview." American Studies (with original typescript and letter), 1974 (Box 240, Folder 4654)
      - West, Richard S. "Ransom Honored by Prof. Daniel and Author Warren." The Kenyon Collegian, 1974 (Box 240, Folder 4655)
      - Unidentified interview: typescript and photocopy, corrected (Box 240, Folder 4656)
      - Unidentified writings and fragments (Box 240, Folder 4657)
      - Miscellaneous, 1948-77, n.d. (Box 240, Folder 4658-61)
- Personal Papers, 1906-89; Series III; 10.5; (22 boxes)
  Series III, Personal Papers, consists of documents, legal papers, photographs, and personal memoranda in the possession of Robert Penn Warren, arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Addresses (Box 241, Folder 4662)
  - Appointment books (Box 241, Folder 4663-64)
  - Awards and Honors
    - Bicentennial Silver Medal (Columbia University), 1954 (Box 241, Folder 4665)
    - Bollingen Prize: publicity, 1967 (Box 241, Folder 4666)
    - John Muir College, Fellow, 1967 (Box 241, Folder 4667)
    - Kentucky State Resolution, 1968 (Box 241, Folder 4668)
    - Lotus Club State Dinner Tribute: centennial brochure and signed menus, 1975 (Box 241, Folder 4669)
    - MacArthur Fellow (John D. and Catherine T. MacArthur Foundation), 1986 (Box 241, Folder 4670)
    - National Book Award: publicity, 1958 (Box 241, Folder 4671)
    - National Medal for Literature: news clippings, 1970 (Box 241, Folder 4672)
    - National Medal of Arts, 1987 (Box 241, Folder 4673)
    - Presidential Medal of Freedom (Box 242, Folder 4674)
    - Pulitzer Prize
      - All the King's Men, 1946 (Box 242, Folder 4675)
      - Promises: publicity, 1957 (Box 242, Folder 4676)
      - Now and Then, 1979 (Box 242, Folder 4677)
    - Robert Meltzer Award (Screenwriters Guild): plaque, 1949 (Box 242, Folder 4678)
    - Robert Penn Warren Day (State of Kentucky), 1985 (Box 242, Folder 4679)
    - Sidney Hillman Foundation Award, 1956 (Box 243, Folder 4680)
    - State of Tennessee. "Honorary Citizen of the State of Tennessee"
      See: Oversize, Box 315, folder 5361
    - Van Wyck Brooks Award for Literary Achievement, 1969 (Box 243, Folder 4681)
    - Wilma and Roswell Messing, Jr. Award (St. Louis University Libraries), 1977 (Box 243, Folder 4682)
    - Others, 1951-89 (Box 243, Folder 4683-86)
  - Biographical information, 1917-87 (Box 244, Folder 4687-88)
  - Birthday tributes
    - Seventy-fifth birthday symposium program, 1980 (Box 244, Folder 4689)
    - Birthday celebration program (St. Andrews Presbyterian College), 1982 (Box 244, Folder 4690)
    - State of Connecticut. Seventy-fifth birthday tribute
      See Oversize, Box 315, folder 5362
    - State of Massachusetts. Eightieth birthday proclamation
      See Oversize, Box 315, folder 5363
  - Classroom material, 1946, 1969 (Box 244, Folder 4691)
  - Family files
    Eleanor Clark Warren
    - "The Art of Adventure." Vogue, 1953 Sep 1 (Box 244, Folder 4692)
    - Reviews, 1952, n.d. (Box 244, Folder 4693)
    - Emma Brescia (Cinina) Warren. Translation of Vittorini, Il Sempione...: typescript, carbon, corrected (with letters from Pier Passinetti), 1950, n.d. (Box 244, Folder 4694-98)
    - Gabriel Warren: French essay (school exercise), n.d. (Box 244, Folder 4699)
    - Rosanna Warren
      - Poems, 1980, n.d. (Box 244, Folder 4700)
      - Translations and reviews, 1983-86 (Box 244, Folder 4701)
  - Warren family history, 1961-86 (Box 244, Folder 4702)
  - Financial papers
    - Bank statements, 1945-60 (Box 245, Folder 4703-13)
    - Bank statements, 1961-65 (Box 246, Folder 4714-18)
    - Cancelled checks, 1946-55 (Box 247, Folder 4719)
    - Cancelled checks, 1956-58 (Box 248, Folder 4720)
    - Cancelled checks, 1959-61 (Box 249, Folder 4721)
    - Cancelled checks, 1962-63 (Box 250, Folder 4722)
    - Financial institutions
      - Irving Trust Company, 1952-89 (Box 251, Folder 4723)
      - Julius Lefkowitz and Company, 1948-78 (Box 251, Folder 4724)
      - Welch and Forbes, 1960-86 (Box 251, Folder 4726-30)
    - Income tax returns and related documents, 1938-81 (Box 251, Folder 4731)
    - Insurance documents, 1953-82 (Box 251, Folder 4732)
    - Ledgers, 1952-57 (Box 251, Folder 4733-34)
    - Publishers' invoices, 1948-80 (Box 252, Folder 4735)
    - Royalty statements
      - Appleton-Century Crofts, 1952-80 (Box 252, Folder 4736)
      - Columbia Pictures ( All the King's Men ), 1951 (Box 252, Folder 4737)
      - Dell Publishing Company, 1961-64 (Box 252, Folder 4738)
      - Harcourt Brace Javonovich, 1953-87 (Box 252, Folder 4739)
      - Random House, 1946-65 (Box 252, Folder 4740-41)
      - William Morris Agency (with other financial documents), 1958-61 (Box 252, Folder 4742-44)
      - Miscellaneous, 1935-68 (Box 252, Folder 4745)
    - Travel receipts and other documents, 1928-62 (Box 252, Folder 4746-51)
    - Travel receipts and other documents, 1952-72 (Box 253, Folder 4752-55)
    - Warren residence (Fairfield, Connecticut), 1953-54 (Box 253, Folder 4756-57)
    - Miscellaneous, 1948-1969 (Box 253, Folder 4758-62)
  - Honorary degrees
    - Berea College, 1978 (Box 253, Folder 4763)
    - Bucknell University, 1977 (Box 253, Folder 4764)
    - Claremont Graduate School, 1982 (Box 253, Folder 4765)
    - Dartmouth College
      See Oversize, Box 315, folder 5364
    - Harvard (announcement). The Harvard Bulletin, 1973 (Box 253, Folder 4766)
    - Johns Hopkins University. "Order of Events": typescript, 1977 (Box 253, Folder 4767)
      See also: Oversize, Box 315, folder 5365
    - New York University, 1983 (Box 253, Folder 4768)
    - Oxford University (Eightieth Anniversary of Rhodes Scholarships). Program, brochure, 1983 (Box 253, Folder 4769)
      See also: Oversize, Box 315, folder 5366
    - Southwestern at Memphis
      - Program, 1974 (Box 253, Folder 4770)
      - Publicity, 1974 (Box 253, Folder 4771)
    - Swarthmore College
      See: Oversize, Box 315, folder 5367
    - Transylvania College, 1980 (Box 253, Folder 4772)
    - University of Louisville, 1949 (Box 253, Folder 4773)
    - University of New Haven, 1974 (Box 253, Folder 4774)
    - University of the South: printed program, 1974 (Box 253, Folder 4775)
    - Wake Forest University: transcript of presentation of award, 1984 (Box 253, Folder 4776)
    - Wesleyan University, 1970 (Box 253, Folder 4777)
    - Yale University: printed program (Box 253, Folder 4778)
      See also: Oversize, box 315, folder 5368
  - Lectures, public readings, symposia (Warren speaking): programs, publicity, 1945-85 (Box 255, Folder 4779-81)
  - Legal documents
    - Publishing contracts, 1949-89 (Box 255, Folder 4782-84)
    - Foreign publication licenses, 1956-65 (Box 255, Folder 4785)
    - Leases, 1951-53 (Box 255, Folder 4786)
    - Miscellaneous, 1952-56 (Box 255, Folder 4787)
  - Literary material
    - Conference on the Defence of Poetry (Harvard Summer School, August 14-17, 1950): printed transcript (Box 255, Folder 4788)
    - The Fugitives: miscellaneous articles, 1964, 1977 (Box 255, Folder 4789)
    - Housman, A. E.: photocopies of poems, n.d. (Box 255, Folder 4790)
    - Pound, Ezra: reviews and essays on Pound collected for Warren by H. Potterfield, 1972-73 (Box 255, Folder 4791)
    - Southern Review: correspondence list (1935-46) (Box 255, Folder 4792)
    - "Writers on Writing" (radio transcript: Yale Reports ), 1962 Feb (Box 255, Folder 4793)
    - Miscellaneous, 1935-89, n.d. (Box 255, Folder 4794)
    - Miscellaneous, 1951-87, n.d. (Box 256, Folder 4795-96)
  - Medical records (Robert Penn Warren, Emma Brescia Warren, Eleanor Clark Warren), 1949-83 (Box 256, Folder 4797)
  - News clippings (miscellaneous), 1947-86 (Box 256, Folder 4798-4800)
  - Negatives: "Brooks Warren"
    See: Oversize, Box 315, folder 5368a
  - Notes for graduate course in eighteenth-century philosophy: holograph and typescript (Box 256, Folder 4801)
  - Photographs
    Robert Penn Warren
    - Individual photographs, 1906-83 (Box 256, Folder 4802-03)
    - See also: Oversize, Box 316, folder 5369
    - Group photographs, 1925-83 (Box 256, Folder 4804-08)
    - See also: Oversize, Box 316, folder 5370
    - News clippings and reproductions, 1948-80, n.d. (Box 256, Folder 4809)
    - Warren family, 1944, n.d. (Box 257, Folder 4810)
    - Eudora Welty: photographs of Katherine Anne Porter (with letter from Welty), 1940?, n.d. (Box 257, Folder 4811)
    - Friends, 1927-67, n.d. (Box 257, Folder 4812)
    - Mark Morrow: photographs of writers, 1987 (Box 257, Folder 4813)
    - William Christenberry. "Southern Photographs."
      See: Oversize, Box 316, folder 5372
    - Miscellaneous photographs, 1959-88, n.d. (Box 257, Folder 4814)
      See also: Oversize, box 316, folder 5373
    - Slides, 1947-76 (Box 257, Folder 4815)
    - Sketches, 1976, 1979 (Box 257, Folder 4816)
      See also: Oversize, Box 316, folders 5370-71
    - Postcards, n.d. (Box 257, Folder 4817)
  - Professional organizations and conferences (minutes, programs, newsletters):
    Academy of American Poets
    - History, 1983 (Box 257, Folder 4818)
    - Nominations for 48th Fellowship, n.d. (Box 257, Folder 4819)
    - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 257, Folder 4820)
    - American Academy of Arts and Sciences Proceedings, 1951 (Box 257, Folder 4821)
    - Connecticut Civil War Centennial Commission, 1960 (Box 257, Folder 4822)
    - Innovation in Higher Education (conference), 1964-65 (Box 257, Folder 4823)
    - Japan Conference on Cultural Interchange, 1962 (Box 257, Folder 4824-26)
    - National Cultural Center, 1960-64 (Box 258, Folder 4827-30)
    - National Institute of Arts and Letters (American Academy of Arts and Letters), 1957-76 (Box 258, Folder 4831-36)
  - Publications checklists, n.d. (Box 259, Folder 4837)
  - Student writings, 1976 (Box 259, Folder 4838)
  - Subject files
    - American Place Theatre (history and commentary): typescript and photocopy (Box 259, Folder 4839)
    - "The Autograph Game", n.d. (Box 259, Folder 4840)
    - Board of Overseers, Harvard College: miscellaneous material, 1965-69 (Box 259, Folder 4841)
    - Civil War documentary (Ken Burns), 1986 (Box 259, Folder 4842)
    - Couch, W. T. (dismissal case): typescript and holograph notes, 1952, n.d. (Box 259, Folder 4843-44)
    - Epilepsy, 1952-54 (Box 259, Folder 4845)
    - Ku Klux Klan: VHS cassette of TV news programs on Klan matters
      See also: Box 333, folder 5374a
    - Library of Congress: "Calls to date on Poet Laureate", 1986 Feb-Mar (Box 259, Folder 4846)
    - Lyndon Johnson--Hubert Humphrey inaugural invitation, 1965 (Box 259, Folder 4847)
    - "Poet's Corner" dedication (St. John the Divine): program and publicity, 1984 (Box 259, Folder 4848)
    - Pulitzer Prize: programs, 1966, n.d. (Box 259, Folder 4849)
    - Questionnaire for writers (with comments by Warren), n.d. (Box 259, Folder 4850)
    - Rhodes Scholarship and reunion, 1983 (Box 259, Folder 4851-52)
    - Smith, James A. (scandal): news clipping, 1939 (Box 259, Folder 4853)
    - Yale Library acknowledgements (with related correspondence), 1958-70 (Box 260, Folder 4854-57)
  - Tributes and memorial services
    - Agee, James. The Harvard Advocate Commemorative to James Agee, 1972 Feb (Box 260, Folder 4858)
    - Auden, W. H. W. H. Auden, 1907-1923. The Harvard Advocate, 1973 (Box 260, Folder 4859)
    - Auden, W. H. "Wystan Hugh Auden, 1907-1973: Memorial Service", 1973 Oct 3 (Box 260, Folder 4860)
    - Cox, Hugh. "In Re: Hugh B. Cox, Deceased.. .Memorial Proceedings... ." (with comments by Warren): typescript, 1973 Oct 24 (Box 260, Folder 4861)
    - Lytle, Andrew. "Andrew Nelson Lytle: A Celebration", 1982 Dec 3 (Box 260, Folder 4862)
    - Wilder, Thornton. "Thornton Niven Wilder, 1907-1975" (memorial program), 1976 Jun 18 (Box 260, Folder 4863)
  - Undergraduate examinations (with Vanderbilt brochure), 1925-26 (Box 260, Folder 4864)
  - Warren birthplace (Guthrie, Kentucky): news clippings, 1987 (Box 260, Folder 4865)
  - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 260, Folder 4866-69)
  - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 261, Folder 4870-80)
  - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 262, Folder 4881-86)
- Writings of Others, 1937-89; Series IV; 7.5; (18 boxes)
  Series IV, Writings of Others, is divided into Writings on Warren, Adaptations of Works by Warren, Essays and Articles (non-Warren), and Essays Annotated by Warren.
  - Writings on Warren
    - Dissertations and book-length studies:
      - Blum, Ida Susan. "Web and Wilderness: The Development of Robert Penn Warren as a Novelist", 1963 (Box 263, Folder 4887)
      - Chrisman, Richard N. "The Gothic Critique of Pastoral in the Poetry of Robert Penn Warren", 1980 (Box 263, Folder 4888)
      - Clark, William Bedford. Untitled work (introduction only): galley proofs, 1981 (Box 263, Folder 4889)
      - Dawson, Gerrit. "Dead Reckoning: The Mundane Asthetics of Robert Penn Warren", 1984 (Box 263, Folder 4890)
      - Konikkara, Cleopatra, Sister. "The Novels of Robert Penn Warren... ."
        - Typescript (incomplete), n.d. (Box 263, Folder 4891)
        - Typescript, carbon (incomplete), n.d. (Box 263, Folder 4892)
      - Leahy, Stephen. "Self-Involvement in History in the Work of Robert Penn Warren", 1981 (Box 264, Folder 4893)
      - Rotella, Guy L. Mediation of the Heart: The Tragic Theme in the Poetry of Robert Penn Warren (Box 264, Folder 4894-97)
      - Tate, Allen. "American Poetry Since 1920." The Bookman, n.d. (Box 264, Folder 4898)
      - Watkins, Floyd. American Poems: typescript, photocopy, n.d. (Box 264, Folder 4899-4900)
    - Essays
      - Allison, Margaret. "'Red' Warren." Northwest Life, 1944 Jul (Box 264, Folder 4901)
      - Bloom, Harold. "Sunset Hawk: Warren's Poetry and Tradition": typescript, 1982 (Box 264, Folder 4902)
      - Bradbury, John M. "Robert Penn Warren's Novels." Accent, 1953 Spring (Box 264, Folder 4903)
      - Broderick, John C. "The Poet Laureate of the United States": typescript and offprint (Box 264, Folder 4904)
      - Brooks, Peter. "Chroniques: Nouvelle Critique et Critique Nouvelle aux États-Unis": photocopy, 1969 (Box 264, Folder 4905)
      - Burke, Kenneth. "As I Was Saying." Michigan Quarterly Review, 1972 Winter (Box 264, Folder 4906)
        - Cambon, Glauco. "Poesia Recentissima E Inedita Di Robert Penn Warren." L'Interpreta (offprint)., [1957?] (Box 264, Folder 4907)
        - Clark, James C. "Through the Pasteboard Masks": typescript, photocopy, 1976 (Box 264, Folder 4908)
        - Clark, William Bedford. "Robert Penn Warren's Love Affair with America" (with Warren's annotations). The Southern Review, 1986 Autumn (Box 264, Folder 4909)
        - Clark, William Bedford. "Warren's Criticism and the Evolving Self." The Kenyon Review, 1989 Winter (Box 264, Folder 4910)
        - Cohen, Joseph. "Robert Penn Warren: At home Among His Homeless Jews" (transcript of speech): typescript, 1987 (Box 264, Folder 4911)
        - Core, George. "Vanderbilt English and the Rise of the New Criticism": typescript, 1987 (Box 264, Folder 4912)
        - Dickey, James. "Robert Penn Warren Symposium Presentation": typescript, 1982 (Box 265, Folder 4913)
        - Four Quartets. Robert Penn Warren Issue, 1972 May (Box 265, Folder 4914)
        - Fridy, Wilford. "Robert Penn Warren and K" [Kent Greenfield]: typescript (Box 265, Folder 4915)
        - Gerard, Albert. "Robert Penn Warren, Romancier de la Responsibilité" Revue Générale Belge (offprint), 1960 (Box 265, Folder 4916)
        - Gilbert, Jess and Stephen M. Brown. "Agrarian Visions Pierce the Dark.. ." (incomplete): typescript., 1979 (Box 265, Folder 4917)
        - "Alternative Land Reform Proposals in the 1930's: The Nashville Agrarians and the Southern Tenant Farmers' Union" (offprint), 1981
        - Grimshaw, James. "Robert Penn Warren's Annus Mirabilis": photocopy, 1979 (Box 265, Folder 4918)
        - Harvard, William C. "The Burden of the Literary Mind: Some Meditations on Robert Penn Warren as Historian", 1963 Autumn (Box 265, Folder 4919)
        - Humbolt, Charles. "The Lost Cause of Robert Penn Warren." Masses and Mainstream (offprint), 1948 Jul (Box 265, Folder 4920)
        - Jackson, Richard. "The Shards of Time: Robert Penn Warren and the Moment of the Self." Southern Humanities Review offprint), 1980 Spring (Box 265, Folder 4921)
        - Kentucky Poetry Review. Robert Penn Warren / Cleanth Brooks Double Issue, 1980 (Box 265, Folder 4922)
        - Kentucky Poetry Review. Robert Penn Warren 75th Birthday Symposium, 1981 (Box 265, Folder 4923)
        - Konikkara, Cleopatra, Sister. "The Moral Vision of Robert Penn Warren... .", 1970 (Box 265, Folder 4924)
        - Lieberman, Laurence. "The Glacier's Offspring: A Reading of Robert Penn Warren's New Poetry", 1980 (Box 265, Folder 4925)
        - Lombardo, Agostino. "Problemi di Storia Letteraria Americana II." Criterio (offprint), 1957 Nov (Box 265, Folder 4926)
        - Lombardo, Agostino. "Poesia di Robert Penn Warren." Criterio (offprint), 1958 Jan (Box 265, Folder 4927)
        - Modern Fiction Studies. "Robert Penn Warren Special Number", 1960 Spring (Box 265, Folder 4928)
        - Morcos, Magdi Louis. "Robert Penn Warren" (transcript of radio presentation): typescript, 1967 (Box 265, Folder 4929)
        - Nakadate, Neil. Review of Caryle Floyd, Then and Now, 1983 (Box 265, Folder 4930)
        - Oney, Steve. "Robert Penn Warren Finds His Place to Come To." Atlantic Journal and Constitution Magazine, 1979 Sep 16 (Box 265, Folder 4931)
        - O'Sheel, Patrick. "Companion to Owls." Humanities, 1974 Feb (Box 265, Folder 4932)
        - O'Sheel, Patrick. "Robert Penn Warren: Creative Energy Spanning Generations": photocopy, 1924 (Box 265, Folder 4933)
        - Parini, Jay. "The Later Poetry of Robert Penn Warren": typescript, 1981 (Box 265, Folder 4934)
        - Perosa, Sergio. Studi Americani 17, 1971 (Box 265, Folder 4935)
        - Plumly, Stanley. "Robert Penn Warren's Vision." The Southern Review (with Warren's annotations) and offprint, 1970 Autumn (Box 265, Folder 4936)
        - Pritchard, William. "Robert Penn Warren's Achievement": typescript (with comments by Warren), n.d. (Box 265, Folder 4937)
        - Quinn, Bernetta, Sister. "Gull Against a Crimson Sky: Birds in the Later Poems of Robert Penn Warren": photocopy, n.d. (Box 265, Folder 4938)
        - Richman, Robert. "Poetry and the Return to Seriousness." The New Criticism: photocopy, 1985 (Box 266, Folder 4939)
        - Rock, Virginia. "Dualism in Agrarian Thought." Mississippi Quarterly (offprint), n.d. (Box 266, Folder 4940)
        - Rosenbloom, Joseph. "Robert Penn Warren at 72." New England (Boston Sunday Globe ), 1977 Apr 17 (Box 266, Folder 4941)
        - Rotella, Guy. "Robert Penn Warren's Tale of Time", 1979 May 8 (Box 266, Folder 4942)
        - Ruane, Elizabeth. "A Poet's View of Political Fact and Fiction." News Hunter, 1974 Nov (Box 266, Folder 4943)
        - Rubin, Louis D. "Fugitives as Agrarians.", 1972 (Box 266, Folder 4944)
        - Rubin, Louis D. "Robert Penn Warren: Vivid Moralist of the Human Heart": typescript, photocopy, 1970 (Box 266, Folder 4945)
        - Savelli, Giovanni. Letteratura Americana, 1956 (Box 266, Folder 4946)
        - Shelby, Robert Michael. "An Open Lesson in Poetic Composition for Robert Penn Warren('s Editors)": typescript, n.d. (Box 266, Folder 4947)
        - Smith, Dave. "A Hero to Younger Poets" (with Warren's annotations). Poetry Society of America Newsletter, 1985 May (Box 266, Folder 4948)
        - Snipes, Katherine. Untitled essay: typescript, 1981 (Box 266, Folder 4949)
        - Spears, Monroe K. "Robert Penn Warren." Sewanee Review: photocopy, 1986 (Box 266, Folder 4950)
        - Spears, Monroe K. "Robert Penn Warren: A Hardy American." Sewanee Review (offprint), 1983 Fall (Box 266, Folder 4951)
        - Stafford, William. "A Note on the Achievement of Robert Penn Warren": typescript, 1970 (Box 266, Folder 4952)
        - Stallman, Robert Wooster. "Robert Penn Warren: A Checklist of His Critical Writings." University of Kansas City Review (offprint), 1947 Autumn (Box 266, Folder 4953)
        - Stewart, John L. "The Achievement of Robert Penn Warren." South Atlantic Quarterly (offprint), 1948 Oct (Box 266, Folder 4954)
        - Stewart, John L. "Robert Penn Warren and the Knot of History." ELA: A Journal of English Literary History (offprint), 1959 (Box 266, Folder 4955)
        - Stitt, Peter. "Robert Penn Warren, The Poet": typescript, photocopy (with letter), 1978 (Box 266, Folder 4956)
        - Strandberg, Victor. "Robert Penn Warren" ( Dictionary of Literary Biography ): photocopy., 1986 (Box 266, Folder 4957)
        - Styron, William. "Admiral Robert Penn Warren and the Snows of Winter.", 1978 (Box 266, Folder 4958)
        - Vanderbilt Poetry Review. Robert Penn Warren Issue, 1977 (Box 266, Folder 4959)
        - Walhout, Clarence P. Untitled essay, 1968 (Box 266, Folder 4960)
        - Ward, William S. "Robert Penn Warren and the Snows of Winter.", 1978 (Box 266, Folder 4961)
        - Watkins, Floyd. "A National Poet" Mississippi Quarterly (photocopy), 1984 (Box 266, Folder 4962)